#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/balamanohar (LinkedIn) sites.google.com/site/balamanohar/ (Personal) www.gatech.edu/ (Company)

## Top Skills

Algorithms
Programming
GUI development

## Languages

English Telugu

Hindi

## Manohar Paluri

Director, Facebook Al Menlo Park

## Summary

My experience spans Computer Vision, Robotics, Machine Learning. I am excited to walk the uncanny valley of research and development, enjoy learning new things while thriving in challenging environments. In my current group we push the frontiers of image, video and multi-modal understanding for the benefit of various products at Facebook as well as the research community at large.

Specialties: Vision, Robotics, Algorithm Development, Programming, Software Engineering, Prototyping.

## Experience

Facebook 8 years 1 month

Director, Artificial Intelligence September 2015 - Present (5 years)

San Francisco Bay Area

I am currently managing the Computer Vision group at Facebook's Applied Machine Learning organization which is part of our Al Organization. My group focuses on pushing state of the art in Machine Vision and our work is used by all of Facebook's family of Apps. We sit at the intersection of research and product and care about pushing the frontiers of computer vision while bringing the value back to people.

Computer Vision Researcher August 2012 - September 2015 (3 years 2 months)

Google Research Intern May 2012 - August 2012 (4 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Working on next generation 3D Maps. Used sparse reconstruction techniques and the Ceres optimization toolkit to have better 3D Maps and showed

Page 1 of 3

the improvements for SF. After I left Google, I was told by my mentor that whatever we built/worked on got shipped to production.

Georgia Institute of Technology Research Assistant August 2009 - June 2012 (2 years 11 months)

Pursuing Computer Vision and Robotics at Georgia Tech.

**IBM Watson Labs** 

Research Intern

May 2010 - August 2010 (4 months)

Summer Internship at Watson labs, Hawthorne, NY. Worked on Video analytics specifically for Video surveillance, anomaly detection.

Sarnoff Corporation

Associate Member Technical Staff

December 2008 - August 2009 (9 months)

Worked on Lidar acquisition, processing projects. Processing involved, extracting objects based on query given 3D data, segmentation of city data into various categories etc.

Sarnoff Innovative Tech. Pvt. Ltd.

Member of Tech. Staff

July 2006 - December 2008 (2 years 6 months)

Worked on various Vision projects and publications. Projects spanned across tracking objects in videos, contour tracking, automated cinematography for sports (specifically basketball, volleyball and football) and various related things.

#### Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

MS, Computer Science · (2009 - 2011)

International Institute of Information Technology

B.Tech, Computer Science · (2002 - 2006)

GSR college

High School, Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry (2000 - 2002)

# Shree Rang Vidhyalaya · (1992 - 2000)

Georgia Institute of Technology

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Computer Science · (2009)